[Music]
aguilos is a kind of low calorie sugar
naturally existing very small quantities
but now industrially produced as a
commercial sweetener said to have
advantages that make it comparable to
erythritol as a sugar substitute
it's said to have anti-diabetic effects
but this was in obese mice
allulose decreases ldl cholesterol
levels in high fat fed hamsters
and is said to have a substantial impact
on obesity in lard munching mice
but what about men and women
in a petri dish allylose inhibits fat
cell precursors from maturing into fat
cells and reduce the amount of fat
accumulation within fat cells here's a
before and after picture with the fat
staining red of swapping in some allelos
for regular sugar
therefore the researchers conclude allos
may be a promising sugar substitute for
an anti-obesity diet but you don't know
until you
put it to the test
they gave people about a teaspoon of
alulus a half hour before eating a meal
and compared to the no sugar control
group the allelos group started burning
more fat the researchers concluded that
allulose enhances after a meal fat
burning indicating that it could be a
novel sweetener to control and maintain
healthy body weight through enhanced
energy metabolism
okay but first of all it was only 15
calories of fat burned over that four
hour period and they didn't burn more
calories overall they just switched from
burning carb calories to fat calories
and so may have just switched back later
on and made up for it later in the day
you can't just look at one meal you need
to track people's actual weight over
time and
here we go a weight reducing effect of a
syrup that included about five percent
allulose compared to high fructose corn
syrup
the results show significant decreases
in body weight body fat and waist
circumference but it was some
proprietary syrup mixture and look
anything would look good against high
fructose corn syrup
this is the study
i've been looking for
evaluating the effect of ielos for fat
mass reduction in humans over a hundred
individuals randomized to a placebo
control sucralose or a teaspoon of
allulose twice a day or one and three
quarter teaspoons twice a day and
despite no change in physical activity
or calorie consumption between the two
groups body fat was significantly
decreased following allulo
supplementation they even took ct scans
so they could tell where the fat was
disappearing from
now the drop in body fat was only about
two pounds over 12 weeks and the drop in
abdominal fat in the higher dose group
was almost totally a drop in
subcutaneous fat the the flabby
superficial fat not the dangerous
visceral fat deeper down that really
matters for health but still body fat
loss despite no change in calorie intake
similar to what was seen in the mice but
the hamster effect did not materialize
no significant change in ldl cholesterol
in either of the allulose groups
what about the purported anti-diabetes
effects if you have people chug a
beverage with up to about two teaspoons
of iolus alone
previously known as psychos or with a
big load of rapidly digesting carbs the
algolos alone has predictably no
influence on blood glucose or insulin
concentrations yet when you consume
allos along with the refined carbs there
is actually a suppression of the
elevation of blood sugar and insulin and
by a significant amount of 30 drop in
blood sugar and insulin levels over a
two hour period
we think it's because the presence of
iolos impairs the absorption of sugar
through the intestinal lining because
they all might be competing for the same
sugar transporter
yeah but who's chugging maltodextrin
what about just like a regular meal
and here we go and in borderline
diabetics who could use some blood sugar
spike suppression a randomized
double-blind placebo-controlled
crossover experiment to see what
drinking one and a quarter teaspoon of
iolose in a cup of tea with a meal would
do and indeed a significant drop to only
about 15 percent you can see how they
tried to exaggerate the y-axis
they also did a second experiment
randomized people to a little over a
teaspoon of iolos three times a day with
meals for 12 weeks
nice to see there didn't appear to be
any adverse side effects but they also
didn't find any weight loss effects in
contrast with that other study so the
body fat data is mixed and so too is the
sugar data this study found no effects
of value loss on blood sugars and
healthy participants though a similar
study on diabetics did
a systematic review of meta-analyses of
all such controlled feeding trials
suggests that the acute benefits on
blood sugars was of borderline
significance and it's unclear whether or
not this alone could translate into
meaningful improvements in blood sugar
control over time so
maybe it's not enough to just add
allulose you might actually have to also
cut out the junk
although ability to suppress blood sugar
responses is one of the most well
studied aspects of allulose i do just
want to cover one last angle the fact
that alkalos extends the life span of a
tiny round worm called c elegans through
a dietary restriction mechanism even
though they ate the same amount of food
two months in just a few percent of the
control group were still alive whereas
twice as many in the low allulose group
and about 25 percent still around in the
higher allulose group
we think it worked boosting the
expression and activities of antioxidant
enzymes in the body extending lifespan
by mopping up free radicals
but who cares about the survival curves
of worms well
c elegans is a well-studied model of
aging and longevity but mostly just for
convenience sake but does share most of
the longevity genes or pathways we're
interested in
be nice to see experiments on at least
human cells
and here we go
the effect of alulos on free radicals
and oxidative stress in human coronary
artery endothelial cells the cells that
line the inside of our arteries add a
bunch of sugar and free radical levels
shoot up but add the same amount of
sugar along with some alus and it's as
if you've never even added the sugar and
this then translates to inhibiting the
expression of an inflammatory marker
that plays a role in the buildup of
atherosclerotic plaque
however it's still too early to draw
conclusions about the clinical relevance
of these data
to conclude are these rare sugars like
allulose healthy alternatives for
traditional sweeteners well
considering the variety of potentially
beneficial effects of iolos without
known disadvantages from metabolic and
toxicological studies alkalos may
currently be the most promising rare
sugar
but how much is that saying
we just don't have a lot of good human
data
as a result of the absence of these
studies it may be too early to recommend
rare sugars for human consumption
[Music]
you